<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elixir on Joser&#39;s Elixir</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/elixir/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elixir on Joser&#39;s Elixir</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/elixir/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Perfect Code Meets Imperfect Hardware: My TSIC306 Temperature Sensor Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tsic306-raspberry-pi-timing-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tsic306-raspberry-pi-timing-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hook-a-tale-of-technical-success-and-practical-failure&#34;&gt;The Hook: A Tale of Technical Success and Practical Failure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent days implementing the ZACWire protocol for a TSIC306 temperature sensor in pure Elixir. The code was elegant. The protocol implementation was correct. The parity checks validated perfectly. Then I deployed it to my Raspberry Pi Zero W and watched it fail 75% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how I learned that sometimes the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; technical implementation meets the &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo; platform constraints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying to Fly.io for Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/deploying-to-flyio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/deploying-to-flyio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-your-app-live-with-flyio&#34;&gt;Getting Your App Live with Fly.io&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to deploying Elixir applications for development, Fly.io stands out as a developer friendly platform that makes the deployment process straightforward. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through deploying my project to Fly.io and share some key learnings along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Credo to Ensure Code Quality in Elixir</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/credo-code-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/credo-code-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-code-quality-matters&#34;&gt;Why Code Quality Matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maintaining code quality is essential for any project that aims to be maintainable and scalable. In the Elixir ecosystem, Credo is the go-to static code analysis tool that helps enforce consistency and catch potential issues before they become problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Credo analyzes your code for readability, refactoring opportunities, software design suggestions, and common mistakes. It&amp;rsquo;s like having an experienced Elixir developer review your code automatically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with Tidewave: Vibe Coding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-web-app-with-tidewave/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-web-app-with-tidewave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tidewave&#34;&gt;What is Tidewave?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tidewave is an AI coding assisstant meant for full stack web development. It is built on top of Elixir and Phoenix by José Valim. What I found different about Tidewave is that it runs insdie of your browser. It is deeply integrated with your web frameworkand easily allows you to see what the coding agent is doing in real time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-with-tidewave&#34;&gt;Getting Started with Tidewave&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we begin, make sure you have:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
